Lee Alan Burton

Personal Details

Nationality: British Place of Birth: U.K.

Email Address: leeburton@shu.edu.cn Twitter Handle: @leeaburton

Office Telephone: +86 021 6613 6129 Website: www.bmd-lab.org

Office Address: E111, Baoshan Campus, Shanghai University, Shanghai, 200444, China.

Google Scholar Page: https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=fEp-jzkAAAAJ&hl=en

Linkedin Profile: http://uk.linkedin.com/in/lee-a-burton/

Professional Summary

Status: Associate Professor (full time).

Affiliations: Member of the Royal Society of Chemistry.

Accolades: - Chinese National Science Foundation International Young Scientist Award 2019.

- Shanghai Municipal Government Eastern Young Scholar Award 2018.

- European Commission Seal of Excellence Award 2017.

- Japanese Material Research Society Award for Encouragement of Materials

Research Science 2012.

Publications: 23 peer-review research articles; 3 international patents covering 13 inventions.

Metrics: More than 1,500 citations, h-index: 16, 4 first-author papers with >130 citations.

Funding Awards: Early career fellowship, 2 International Research Fellowships, PhD Scholarship.

Languages: English (native), French (conversational), Mandarin (basic).

Qualifications

Doctoral Qualification: PhD in Sustainable Chemical Technologies, University of Bath, UK.

Undergraduate Degree: Master of Chemistry (Hons), University of Warwick, UK.Other Qualifications: Master of Research (Merit), University of Bath, UK.

Diplôme d'Études en Langue Française (B1), Université Catholique de Louvain.

Key Skills Summary

- Project management, team-leading, task delegation and international collaboration.
- Programming proficiency in Python 2/3, Bash and LaTeX languages.
- Project proposal, bid evaluation and persuasive writing.
- Control of Substances Hazardous to Health (COSHH) and risk assessment practices.
- Numerical and technical analysis, software and computer literacy.
- Budget management, resource allocation and account keeping.
- Multi-disciplinary teamwork, event organisation and laboratory management roles.
- Presentation and public engagement experience, 3D visualisation software, image rendering.
- Teaching, lecturing, online recording and demographic awareness.

Employment History

Feb. 2019 to Present – Associate Professor, Shanghai University, China.

- Recipient of Shanghai Eastern Young Scholar early career fellowship, 2019.
- Recipient of the Chinese National Science Foundation International Young Scientist Award, 2019.
- Tenured faculty position in the Department of Physics and guest lecturer in international development.
- Tutorial leader at the 2019 Jiangsu mathematics & computing in materials design graduate summer school.
- Invited speaker at two international conferences and one international workshop.
- Recipient of Royal Society of Chemistry small equipment research fund.
- Invited article selected as cover feature for J. Mat. Chem. C. emerging investigators special issue 2020.
- Contributed article selected as cover feature for J. Phys. Chem. Lett. 2020.

Dec. 2016 to Feb. 2019 – Research Fellow, Université Catholique de Louvain, Belgium.

- Recipient of "Move-In Louvain" research fellowship funded by the EU Marie-Curie actions.
- Recipient of the European Commission Seal of Excellence award 2018.
- Invited speaker & session chair at European Materials Research Society (E-MRS) Meetings 2017 & 2018.

Lee Alan Burton

- B1 level Diplôme d'Études en Langue Française (DELF) qualification obtained.
- 2 international patents granted, contribution purchased by Panasonic Corporation.
- Tutorial leader on database querying & high-throughput screening at Materials Research Society (MRS)
 Spring Meeting, USA, 2018.

Nov. 2014 to Nov. 2016 –Research Fellow, Tokyo Institute of Technology, Japan.

- Royal Society nominated candidate for maximally funded fellowship with Japanese Society for the Promotion of Science (JSPS).
- Equal shareholder on international patent for 11 novel semiconductors (number WO/2017/065294).
- Speaker at four international conferences and invited contribution to international workshop.
- 5 research articles published in high impact journals including Nature Comms. and Phys. Rev. Lett.
- Japanese language classes and culture engagement activities attended throughout the fellowship.
- Volunteer participant of JSPS Science Dialogue program: lecturing at senior high schools (ages 15-17).

Oct. 2010 to Oct. 2014 - Doctoral Student, University of Bath, UK.

- Multi-disciplinary PhD funded by Engineering and Physical Sciences Research Council scholarship.
 - Recipient of Award for Encouragement of Materials Research Science by Japanese Materials Research Society.
 - o Over 2,000 GBP in external grant money and bursary awards.
- Laboratory custodian of Solar Instrument Room, Department of Chemistry.
 - o Developed control and safety standards for contemporary lab space.
 - o Implemented training and operating protocols for hazardous experimental procedures.
- Public engagement and ambassadorial roles for the Centre for Sustainable Chemical Technologies.
 - o Elected Ambassador to the UK Energy Research Network for the Bath graduate school.
 - o Invited speaker for the British Science Association's 'Science Café' public presentation.
 - o University of Bath STEM (Science, Technology, Engineering and Mathematics) ambassador.
- Casual Demonstrator and teaching assistant.

Dec. 2013 to May 2014 - Events Manager, "Pint of Science" festival, Bath, UK.

• Theme leader of 'Planet Earth' section, Bath chapter, for international science festival 'Pint of Science'.

Nov. 2013 to Apr. 2014 – Conference Organiser, Royal Society of Chemistry, UK.

- Organising committee member for the RSC, Solid State Group Easter Meeting, Buckinghamshire, UK.
- Responsibilities included: budget allocations, costing, talk selection and program design.

Jul. 2013 to Dec. 2013 - Visiting Scholar, Harvard University, USA.

- Established international collaboration between the University of Bath (UK), Harvard University (USA) and the Massachusetts Institute of Technology (USA).
- Involved multiple visits between UK & USA, confidential data handling and regular teleconferencing.

Oct. 2010 to Sep. 2011 - Master of Research, University of Bath, UK.

• Degree with taught courses and 2 research projects: battery cathodes and materials for hydrogen storage.

Apr. 2009 to Sep. 2009 - Research Intern, University of Tasmania, Australia.

• Designed and built a 2-D gas chromatography suite to analyse oil spills for the Australian Antarctic Division.

References on Request **Professor Aron Walsh**, **Professor Fumiyasu Oba Professor Jeffrey Reimers** (PhD Supervisor) (Post-Doctoral Supervisor) (Current Institute Director) Laboratory for Materials & Structures. Royal School of Mines. School of Mathematical and Imperial College London, Tokyo Institute of Technology, Physical Sciences, 638 Jones London, SW7 2BP, Yokohama 226-8503, Street, Broadway, Sydney, United Kingdom. Australia. Japan. a.walsh@imperial.ac.uk oba@msl.titech.ac.jp jeffrey.reimers@uts.edu.au